Uh well the first thing you probably
want should know about functions is that
you've actually already been using them.
Um so for example when I told you if you
type alert and you see this little box
that is a function. So when we type
alert we can give it some information.
It will take that input do some work and
give us some output. The output that it
gives is a popup box that says whatever
we type in here. So if we type hello
world um we'll get hello world. Um,
if you want to um
if you want to prompt someone for
information, you probably used a
different um function. And this one
takes an input as well. Um,
and it shows it takes an input, does
some work. The work it does is it shows
a pop-up box with an input box inside of
it, and it shows your custom message.
So, this one takes an input, does some
work, and gives you some output. And
actually this one does something that we
call returning. So it returns some
output. So it does this function, it
does some work, someone types something
into it and then it gives the result of
that back to your variable. So I could
store it by saying let my var equal
prompt. So I take a prompt, I ask the
user for information, it enters that
information and then the result of that
is returned to my variable. So now my
variable is storing the result of the
prompt.
You've also used some other ones. So for
example, parse int takes in a string and
gives you back a number. Um and you can
store that number by saying let my num
equal parse int. Parse float is another
one we've used. Um maybe if we think
about strings, say my string
hello strings have some built-in
functions. So you can say my string dot
um to lowercase and what that does is it
takes this string converts it to
lowercase and then returns it and we can
store it. So we can say let new string
equal my string. So it takes the string
as an input turns it into lowercase and
then returns it and we store it in new
string. So if you've been using
functions all along then why are we
having a discussion about functions?
Well, the reason we're discussing
functions is we're going to show you how
to build your own custom functions so
that you can take pieces of code that
you use over and over and repeat them.
So, someone out there said, "Man, we
keep showing all of these pop-up boxes.
Wouldn't it be nice if we could just
type the word alert rather than writing
all the code for a pop-up box every
time?" Um, someone else said, "Wow,
we're prompting a lot of people for
information. be nice if instead of
typing all the code to make that pop-up
box show, I could just type the word
prompt and have it work. Well, we can do
the same thing. So, how do you write a
function? Well, you start by using the
keyword function. Say function and then
you give your function a name. Um, by
convention in JavaScript, your function
names should probably start with a
lowercase character. Um, generally they
use camelc case in JavaScript, which
means that you start your function with
a lowercase letter, but then each
additional word in your function name is
marked by an uppercase letter. So if I
wanted to create a function that added
two numbers, I would say add two
numbers. Um, and then the next thing you
need to do is you need to put
parentheses
and then you need to put curly braces.
So now we have successfully created a
function called add two numbers. And we
could call this function. We could say
add two numbers put parenthesis.
Um and just to show you that it is in
fact a function. You'll notice that it
is marked with a cube here and not this
square. This is a function. We can call
it. We can put parenthesis and it will
do something.
So the question is what does this
function do? Well, right now absolutely
nothing. Um, if you look inside these
curly braces, this is the code that runs
when you call the function. And right
now, our code does absolutely nothing.
Um, in the next video we'll talk about
how you can make your function do